Local 1199 Moe Foner Photographs 6140 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Local 1199 Moe Foner Photographs
1955
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees (NUHHCE)
Local 1199 Drug amd Hospital Union
6140 P
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Photographs.
6694526
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 07, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 23, 2016
Biographical / Historical
As a local of the Drug, Hospital, and Health Care Employees Union, Local 1199 was founded by Leon J. Davis in 1932, to organize pharmacists in New York City. Nonprofessional hospital employees were organized starting in 1958.
Because of the large number of Black and Puerto Rican workers it sparked the first postware Civil Rights Movement. May 8, 1959 marks the start of approximately 3500 hospital workers striking against seven large private hospitals in New York City, the strike lasted forty-six days.
Professional and technical workes were added to the union in 1963, the same year they won the right to collective bargaining under provisions of the state's labor relations act. The union was granted the right to represent workers across the state in 1965. Registered nurses became part of the union in 1973.
In 1998 the union became part of SEIU and membership went up significantly.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes photographs of Moe Foner, Leon Davis, Ossie and Ruby Dee Davis, others such as Coretta Scott King, and the Rev. Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Photographs from strikes, union meetings, rallies, and miscellaneous.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6085 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project "Frederick Douglass and His Time" Posters 6084 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Women of Hope Poster Sets 6089 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Posters 6069: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Additional Files 6140 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio Recordings 6140: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project 5929 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs 5929: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Records 6169 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 6169: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Files 6169 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia 6169 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs 5929 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 5929 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia
Labor unions -- Health facilities -- New York (State); Foner, Moe, 1915-; Bread and Roses Cultural Project -- Photographs; National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees -- Photographs; National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees. Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union (New York, N.Y.) -- Photographs
6694526
- Angelou, Maya - 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  2 photographs
- Baltimore election (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bread and Roses (Box 1, Folder 3)
  13 photographs
- Celebrations (Box 1, Folder 4)
  5 photographs
- Columbia University (Box 1, Folder 5)
  3 photographs
- Davis, Leon (Box 1, Folder 6)
  17 photographs
- Davis, Ossie and Ruby Dee (Box 1, Folder 7)
  4 photographs
- Early 1199 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  11 photographs
- Foner, Moe (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Gallery 1199 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  19 photographs
- Godoff, Elliott-Tribute (Box 1, Folder 11)
- King, Coretta Scott (Box 1, Folder 12)
  9 photographs
- King, Jr., Rev. Dr. Martin Luther -- Photographs (Box 1, Folder 13)
  12 photographs
- Labor Arts + Humanities (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Levison, Stanley (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Like a beautiful child (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Local 65 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- NAACP (Box 1, Folder 18)
  8 photographs
- Personalities (Box 1, Folder 19)
  20 photographs
- Rallies (Box 2, Folder 1)
  15 photographs
- Saturday Night Club (Box 2, Folder 2)
  6 photographs
- Stern, Andrew (Box 2, Folder 3)
  1 photograph
- Strike - 1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Strike - 1969, Charleston (Box 2, Folder 5)
  25 photographs
- Strikes, no dates (Box 2, Folder 6)
  10 photographs
- "Take Care" photographs, no date (Box 2, Folder 7)
- "Take Care", 1980 - Photos (Box 2, Folder 8)
- "Take Care, Take Care" 1982, Photographs (Box 2, Folder 9)
  7 photographs
- Theatre - 1199 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Union Meetings (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Workers on the job (Box 2, Folder 12)
  22 photographs